# PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

► British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

**O** github.com/McFunshine

## Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors. For the past half decade, focused on Java/Kotlin development and AI solutions. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI and emerging technology solutions while maintaining focus on practical business outcomes. Hardworking, adaptable and committed to continuous professional development.

### Experience

#### Khonraad Software Engineering

Lead AI and Emerging Technologies Architect

 $Amers foort, \ The \ Netherlands \\ Apr \ 2019-Present$ 

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Updated software to comply with new laws within core Java product development team
- Responsible for complete development lifecycle of the innovation projects, including:
  - A full-featured iOS and Android App using Kotlin Multiplatform with OpenAI integration
  - OCR integration solutions
  - Domain-specific language extension for Decision Engine using JetBrains MPS

#### Captain McFunshines Software Engineering

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Developed Podmorph, an AI-powered solution for podcast and radio professionals
- Integrated multiple AI services (Anthropic, Google AI, OpenAI, Groq, Replit, Fal AI) deployed on AWS and Azure

#### **Baker Hughes**

Senior .Net Developer

Delft, The Netherlands Jan 2014 – Apr 2019

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Developer and Product Evangelist of a subsurface modelling platform for the oil industry

#### Kempen & Co

 $Senior\ .Net\ Developer$ 

Amsterdam, The Netherlands
May 2007 – Dec 2013

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

- Various internal projects to manage large portfolios and indexing products

Unisys

Developer

alagies VDA WebIntelligence C#

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands May 2001 – May 2007

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Reporting developer for world wide Accounts Receivables

**ACT Financial Systems** 

London, UK

Developer Nov 1999 – Apr 2001

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

Developer and supporting Engineer for a stockbroking settlement system

**HSBC** Investment Bank

London, UK

Developer Feb~1999-Nov~1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developer for message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers Support / Business Analyst London, UK

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Support and Report Developer for internal customers

### Education

#### Universiteit van Amsterdam

Masters Software Engineering

Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 2022

- Thesis: Projecting Rules: Improving Comprehension of Business Rules with Projectional Editing Making the Drools DSL Projectional with MPS
- Relevant Module: Software Evolution Used language workbenches to measure the evolution of a large Java codebase

Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University

BA European Business Administration

Hogeschool Holland

HEAO Joint European Business Administration

Wolverhampton, U.K. Graduated 1996 Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 1996

## Certifications

- $-\ 15$  Microsoft Certifications including 5 MCPDs in Windows, Web and Azure
- $-\,$  Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

## Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue

- **Dutch:** Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written